Register of the Kurt Robert Mattusch Papers, 1919-1969.
Hoover Institution Archives
Kurt Robert Mattusch Papers,
1919-1969
81096
Mattusch, Kurt R. (Kurt Robert)
23 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 envelope (11 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, notes, printed matter, and maps, relating to economic conditions in Germany and the United States in the 1930s and 1940s, the postwar occupation of Germany, the transition of India to independence, postwar economic conditions in South Korea, and the New York City politician Raymond V. Ingersoll.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Ingersoll, Raymond Vail, 1875-1940.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--Germany.; Germany.; Germany--Economic conditions.; India.; India--History--20th century.; Korea.; Korea--Economic conditions--1945-; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Economic conditions.; New York (State); Economists.
Biographical Note
1898 Born
1928 Ph.D., University of Wisconsin, Madison
1933-1937 Economic Counsellor, U.S. State Department, American Consulate General, Berlin, Germany
1945-1949 Staff member of Civil Administration Division of U.S. Military Government in Germany, Berlin, Germany
1949-1959 Senior Analyst on India and South Asia, U.S. State Department, Washington, D.C.
1959-1961 Economic Counsellor, U.S. Operations Mission to Korea, Seoul, Korea
1961-1963 Director, Korean Economic Research Center, Seoul, Korea
1979, April 27 Died, Fairfax, Virginia
Series Description
- Correspondence, 1933-1949. (Box No. 1-2.)
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
- Speeches and Writings, 1928-1963. (Box No. 2-11.)
  Drafts and printed copies of articles, books, radio broadcasts, and speeches with correspondence, notes, posters, and reviews relating to them, arranged chronologically by date of publication or writing.
- Lectures and Notes. (Box No. 11-13.)
  Handwritten and typewritten notes, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Subject File, 1924-1963. (Box No. 13-22.)
  Charts, clippings, correspondence, maps, memoranda, notes, printed matter, proposals, reports, summaries of conferences and discussions, unpublished writings of others, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Oversize File. (Box No. 23.)
  Charts, maps, summary of a conference, arranged alphabetically by form.
- Audio-Visual. (Box No. 10. A-V)
  Photographs, arranged by subject.
- Increment. (Box No. 22 & 24.)
  January 1984.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - General (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Unidentified, 1933-1948 (18) (Folder 2)
  - Antia, F. P., 1958 (1) (Folder 3)
  - Basch, R. L., 1938 (1) (Folder 4)
  - Bauch, Konrad, n.d. (1) (Folder 5)
  - Becker, Rudolf, 1934-1938 (19) (Folder 6)
  - Beheim-Schwarzbach, Eberhard, 1937 (2) (Folder 7)
  - Bethke, Vice-President of East Prussia, 1935 (1) (Folder 8)
  - Bishoff, Alfred, 1946 (1) (Folder 9)
  - Blank, Wilhelm K., 1942 (1) (Folder 10)
  - Boeckh, Joachim G., 1946-1947 (4) (Folder 11)
  - Boehmer, Hanz, 1938 (1) (Folder 12)
  - Boone, Perley, 1929 (2) (Folder 13)
  - /Bosse/, Lothar, 1937? (2) (Folder 14)
  - Bringer, Hans, 1946 (1) (Folder 15)
  - Bronisch, S. P., 1947 (2) (Folder 16)
  - Chilian, Erich, 1947-1948 (5) (Folder 17)
  - Coar, John Firman, 1935 (1) (Folder 18)
  - Deutscher Academischer Austauschdienst E. V., 1933 (1) (Folder 19)
  - Domeratzky, Louis, 1938 (1) (Folder 20)
  - Drescher, Leo, 1939, (2) (Folder 21)
  - Drube, Herbst, 1946 (3) (Folder 22)
  - Dunker, Rudolf, 1941-1946 (2) (Folder 23)
  - Dunn, Frederick, n.d. (1) (Folder 24)
  - Eisenberg, Molly, 1935-1938 (4) (Folder 25)
  - Eklund, Dorothy, 1938 (2) (Folder 26)
  - Elliot, John, 1948 (3) (Folder 27)
  - Engel, Ilse, 1938-1939 (3) (Folder 28)
  - Faerber, Hans, 1933 (3) (Folder 29)
  - Finkel, Herr, 1949 (1) (Folder 30)
  - First National Bank & Trust Co., New Canaan, Connecticut, 1939-1940 (8) (Folder 31)
  - Fox, Hugh Corby, 1937 (1) (Folder 32)
  - Fraenkel, Marta, 1938-1946 (3) (Folder 33)
  - Friedeman, Greta, 1937-1940 (10) (Folder 34)
  - Friedeman, Margot, 1947 (2) (Folder 35)
  - Friedeman, Otto, 1938-1946 (10) (Folder 36)
  - Frye, Myrton, 1939 (5) (Folder 37)
  - /Fuchs/, Hans, 1934-1941 (8) (Folder 38)
  - Furtwaengler, E. J., 1933 (1) (Folder 39)
  - Ganger, S., 1947 (1) (Folder 40)
  - Geissler, W., 1933 (1) (Folder 41)
  - Geist, Raymond, 1938 (1) (Folder 42)
  - German Consulate General, New York City, 1938 (8) (Folder 43)
  - Grey, Mary B., 1938 (1) (Folder 44)
  - Griffin, Eleann, n.d. (1) (Folder 45)
  - Habbel, Franz Ludwig, 1946-1947 (5) (Folder 46)
  - Hanstein, Wolfgang, 1948 (1) (Folder 47)
  - Harmon Foundation, 1934-1936 (7) (Folder 48)
  - Hediger, Ernest, 1937-1948 (3) (Folder 49)
  - Heinemann, Helmut, 1937-1969 (17) (Folder 50)
  - Heinemann, Lothar, 1948 (2) (Folder 51)
  - Heinrich, Walter, 1936-1938 (4) (Folder 52)
  - Hess, Rudolf, 1933 (1) (Folder 53)
  - Hewschenhausen, K., 1936 (2) (Folder 54)
  - Hildenbrock, Benno, 1936-1938 (3) (Folder 55)
  - Hinze, Kurt F., 1938 (2) (Folder 56)
  - Hoerwitz, Leo, 1938 (2) (Folder 57)
  - Hoffman, Karl, 1938 (2) (Folder 58)
  - Hoffman, Lilly, 1938-1939 (3) (Folder 59)
  - Holland, J., 1939 (1) (Folder 60)
  - Interessengemeinschaft Farbenindustrie, 1938 (1) (Folder 61)
  - Irani, Marie, 1958 (1) (Folder 62)
  - Janowski, Frau, 1938 (3) (Folder 63)
  - Kaiser, Guenther, 1947 (1) (Folder 64)
  - Karliczek, H. G., 1934 (1) (Folder 65)
  - Kartzke, George, 1937 (1) (Folder 66)
  - Kauffman, Karl, 1938-1939 (3) (Folder 67)
  - Kauffman, Meinhard, 1937-1938 (3) (Folder 68)
  - Klingerberg, R., 1947-1948 (2) (Folder 69)
  - Knappe, Richard, 1946-1947 (5) (Folder 70)
  - Knox, J. A., 1938-1939 (6) (Folder 71)
  - Koch, Ernst, 1933-1948 (4) (Folder 72)
  - Kuegler, Hermann, 1932-1948 (23) (Folder 73)
  - Laidler, Harry W., 1937 (1) (Folder 74)
  - Lausberg, F. & Co., 1948 (2) (Folder 75)
  - Lehfeldt, Hans M., 1936-1939 (4) (Folder 76)
  - Leverich, Henry, 1938 (3) (Folder 77)
  - The Liberal Club, 1938-1939 (10) (Folder 78)
  - Liebman, Julius, 1939 (3) (Folder 79)
  - Loeb, Herr, 1938 (1) (Folder 80)
  - Loose, Gerhard, 1938 (3) (Folder 81)
  - McGreror, D. A., 1939 (1) (Folder 82)
  - Marx, Lise, 1937 (2) (Folder 83)
  - Mason, John Brown, 1938 (2) (Folder 84)
  - /Mattusch/, Fritz, 1936 (1) (Folder 85)
  - /Mattusch/, Gertrude, 1940-1946 (8) (Folder 86)
  - Memmelsdorf, Francisc, 1940 (3) (Folder 87)
  - Mentzel, Horst Eberhardt, 1933-1938 (32) (Folder 88)
  - Messersmith, Sir, 1937 (1) (Folder 89)
  - Moenning, R., 1938 (2) (Folder 90)
  - Mommsen, Theodor, 1938-1940 (2) (Folder 91)
  - Mossner, Karl Eugen, 1938-1939 (7) (Folder 92)
  - Nabel, Kurt, 1933-1948 (21) (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - New Haven, Connecticut, Office of Tax Collector,1938 (2) (Folder 2)
  - Nothingham, Jane, 1936 (2)4Obegard, Peter H., 1938 (5) (Folder 3)
  - Oberfeldt, Lothar, 1935 (1) (Folder 5)
  - Ogg, Frederic A., 1938 (3) (Folder 6)
  - Palyi, Melchior, 1939 (4) (Folder 7)
  - Paslovski, Dr., 1939 (1) (Folder 8)
  - Pech, Johannes, 1937-1948 (25) (Folder 9)
  - Pelle, George, 1947 (2) (Folder 10)
  - Perlman, S., 1934-1937 (2) (Folder 11)
  - Pohlers, W., 1946-1947 (2) (Folder 12)
  - Rakieten, M. L., 1939 (9) (Folder 13)
  - Riesman, Professor, 1938 (1) (Folder 14)
  - Rocholl, Erick, 1946 (1) (Folder 15)
  - Rocholl, Heinrich, 1947 (1) (Folder 16)
  - Roehl, Kurt, 1938 (15) (Folder 17)
  - Roehrig, H. W., 1947-1948 (7) (Folder 18)
  - Rosenstock, Huessy, 1938 (5) (Folder 19)
  - Ruediger, Annemari, 1946-1948 (4) (Folder 20)
  - Sattler, Willi, 1934-1935 (10) (Folder 21)
  - Schlittgen, Hans Joachim, 1947-1949 (3) (Folder 22)
  - Schmidt, Pfarrer, 1935 (1) (Folder 23)
  - Schroeder, Annelise, 1938 (1) (Folder 24)
  - Schuke-Frowz, More, n.d. (1) (Folder 25)
  - Schulze, Frau, 1939 (1) (Folder 26)
  - Schuman, H., 1939 (1) (Folder 27)
  - Seeger, Gerhardt, 1947 (2) (Folder 28)
  - Seidelman, Karl, 1933-1948 (4) (Folder 29)
  - Sharp, Walter, 1927-1947 (5) (Folder 30)
  - Sierig, Karl-Otto, 1946-1947 (3) (Folder 31)
  - Silberstein, Henry A., 1936-1939 (2) (Folder 32)
  - Smith, Jane, 1955 (1) (Folder 33)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1939 (2) (Folder 34)
  - Spykman, Nicholas J., 1939 (1) (Folder 35)
  - Stagen, Oskar, 1937 (1) (Folder 36)
  - Straus, Robert K., 1937 (1) (Folder 37)
  - U.S. Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1938 (1) (Folder 38)
  - Veithard, Martin E., 1947 (2) (Folder 39)
  - Von Balz, Herr, 1936 (1) (Folder 40)
  - Von Trotha, Adolf, 1935 (1) (Folder 41)
  - Walby, Anne Mary, 1934-1937 (5) (Folder 42)
  - Waldman, Guido, 1946-1947 (7) (Folder 43)
  - Walker, Irene, n.d. (1) (Folder 44)
  - Weisser, Kurt, 1947-1948 (5) (Folder 45)
  - Werner, Heinz, 1936-1939 (2) (Folder 46)
  - Wiebalk, Dorte, 1947-1948 (8) (Folder 47)
  - Wilson, Woodside, 1937-1939 (4) (Folder 48)
  - Winkler, Karl, 1939-1947 (5) (Folder 49)
  - Winness, Else, 1938 (2) (Folder 50)
  - Winnschuh, Joseph, 1948 (6) (Folder 51)
  - Yale University, 1938 (1) (Folder 52)
  - Zimmerman, Herr, 1946 (Folder 53)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS. See also SUBJECT FILE -- Korea -- Agencies -- Economic Research Center
  - General (Box 2.)
    - Correspondence
      - n.d. (Folder 54)
      - 1937 (Folder 55)
      - 1938 (Folder 56)
      - 1939-1948 (Folder 57)
    - Lists of Publications (Folder 58)
    - Notes (Folder 59)
    - Poster (Folder 60)
    - Receipts (Folder 61)
  - "Deutsche Industrie und Landschaft," series of lectures on 9 German provinces, n.d. Typescript (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - "British Policy Relating to the Administration of India, 1905-1924," Ph.D. thesis, 1928. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "Die Arbeitslager der buendischen Jugend," Der Jungdeutsche, March-April 1930. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Krisenbericht aus U.S.A.," 11 February 1933. Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Die Bankenkrise in Michigan," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 17 February 1933. Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Kautschuk-Dollar -- Kautschuk-Politik," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 17 February 1933. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Russland als Kunde und Lieferant," Industrie und Handel, 5 and 7 August 1933. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Vereinigte Staaten -- der Feldzug gegen die Arbeitslosigkeit," 11 August 1933. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Roosevelts Kampf gegen die Wirtschaftskrise," Deutsche Sparkassen-Zeitung, 22 August 1933. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Annie Besant," Boersen Courier, 21 September 1933. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "Ergebnisse des Roosevelt-Programms," Deutsche Sparkassen Zeitung, 14 November 1933. Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - Opening address at the conference "Unternehmertum und Jugend," 1934. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Staat und Wirtschaft in Amerika," Mitteilungen der Industrie- und Handelskammer zu Berlin, 25 January 1934. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Nach einem Jahr Roosevelt," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichte, 13 February 1934. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "USA -- Arbeiterschaft im 'Neuem Spiel'," Berliner Tagblatt, 17 March 1934. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "Wirtschafts- und Finanzbericht fuer Februar und Maerz 1934," April, 1934 (?) Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "Plannmaessige Unmsiedlung in USA," Berliner Tagblatt, 12 April 1934. Printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, May 1934. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Amerikanische Siedlugsplane," Berliner Tagblatt, 14 May 1934. Printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, May 1934. Printed copy (Folder 20)
  - "Virgin Islands, das Armenhaus der USA," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 3 June 1934. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, July 1934. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, August 1934. Printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Amerika's Kongress tagt," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, January 1935. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, January 1935. Printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, February 1935. Printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "Roosevelt -- rechts oder links?" Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 9 February 1935. Printed copy (Folder 27)
  - "Die Hintergruende des Goldklausel-Urteils," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, March 1935. Printed copy (Folder 28)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, April 1935. Printed copy (Folder 29)
  - "Die neue Zeit in USA," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 13 April 1935. Printed copy (Folder 30)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, May 1935. Printed copy (Folder 31)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, June 1935. Printed copy (Folder 32)
  - "The Third Reich's Social Policy," June 1935. Typescript (Folder 33)
  - "Die Maschinerie der amerikanischen Handelspolitik," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 27 June 1935. Printed copy (Folder 34)
  - "Handel und Freundshaft mit Amerika," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 9 July 1935. Printed copy (Folder 35)
  - "Roosevelts Kampf," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 12 July 1935. Printed copy (Folder 36)
  - "Offene Tuer, aber schwarze Liste," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 14 July 1935. Printed copy (Folder 37)
  - Untitled writing on impact of Depression of 1930s on American youth, Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 19 July 1935. Printed copy (Folder 38)
  - "Im Kampf gegen Naturgewalten," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 24 July 1935. Printed copy (Folder 39)
  - "Erhoehter Aussenhandel im July," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 15 August 1935. Printed copy (Folder 40)
  - "Gefahrenmomente im Wiederaufbau der deutschen Wirtschaft," Volk und Fuehrung, 22 August 1935. Typescript (Folder 41)
  - "Sicherheit fuer Alle," Breslauer Neueste Nachrichten, 4 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 42)
  - "Roosevelts soziale Revolution," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 6 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 43)
  - "Der Aufbau der amerikanischen Ruestungsindustrie," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 10 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 44)
  - "Roosevelt -- mit und ohne Kongress," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 11 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 45)
  - "Starke Ausfuhr der amerikanischen Ruestungsindustrie," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 17 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 46)
  - "Der 'Diktator von Louisiana'," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 19 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 47)
  - "Recht und Richter in Amerika," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 24 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 48)
  - "Ein amerikanischer Lebenslauf -- Der Weg des Regisseurs W. S. van Dyke," Kunst und Unterhaltung, 25 September 1935. Printed copy (Folder 49)
  - "Isoliert sich Amerika?" Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 17 October 1935. Printed copy (Folder 50)
  - "Freundschaft, aber kein Buendnis," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 23 October 1935. Printed copy (Folder 51)
  - "'Ich bin ein guter Nachbar' -- Amerikas Neutralitaets- politik," Hamburger Anzeiger, 27 October 1935. Printed copy (Folder 52)
  - "Roosevelts Wahlstrategie," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 28 October 1935. Printed copy (Folder 53)
  - "Neuer Meistbeguenstigungspartner der USA," 29 October 1935. Printed copy (Folder 54)
  - "Die Lage in USA," 13 November 1935. Printed copy (Folder 55)
  - "Arbeitslosigkeit trotz Wirtschaftsaufschwung in Amerika," Kieler Neueste Nachrichten, 14 November 1935 (Folder 56)
  - "Roosevelts drei 'R'," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 28 October 1935. Printed copy (Folder 57)
  - "Das Ende von Ottawa?" Weltwirtschaft, December 1935. Printed copy (Folder 58)
  - "Personalle Klaerung in der amerikanischen Handels- politik," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 5 December 1935. Printed copy (Folder 59)
  - "Arbeitslosigkeit und Aufschwung," Muenchner Neueste Nachrichten, 8 December 1935. Printed copy (Folder 60)
  - "Kanadas Weg zurueck," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 10 December 1935. Printed copy and typescript (Folder 61)
  - "Von Ottawa nach Washington," Ruhr und Rhein, 20 December 1935. Printed copy and typescript (Folder 62)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, January 1936. Printed copy (Folder 63)
  - Untitled writing on United States' participation in World War, 1914-1918, Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 26 January 1936. Printed copy (Folder 64)
  - "Inflation in Amerika?" Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 29 January 1936. Printed copy (Folder 65)
  - "Der New Deal vorm Richterstuhl," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 29 January 1936. Printed copy (Folder 66)
  - "Droht Inflation in USA?" Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 31 January 1936. Printed copy (Folder 67)
  - "Economic Review -- the Ruhr Basin," Germany and You, February 1936. Printed copy (Folder 68)
  - "Rundfunk in Amerika," Rufer und Hoerer, February 1936. Printed copy (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - "Der Marsch der Veteranen," Hamburger Anzeiger, 1-2 February 1936. Printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "Krieg und Geschaft in USA," Kieler Neueste Nachrichten, 9 February 1936. Printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Roosevelts Sieg ueber die Power-Trusts," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 19 February 1936. Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Revolution durch Elektrizitaet," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 22 February 1936. Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, March 1936. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Absage Amerikas an dis Inflation," Muenchner Neueste Nachrichten, 9 March 1936. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Dollardeckung 170%" Ruhr und Rhein, 13 March 1936. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Amerikanische Handelsvertraege," Ruhr und Rhein, 27 March 1936. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, April 1936. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "Economic Review," Germany and You, May 1936. Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "Der Wiederaufbau Amerika's," 26 May 1936. Holograph (Folder 12)
  - "Wie lebt ein Arbeitsloser in USA?" Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 5 June 1936. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Juwelen fuer Sardinen," Ruhr und Rhein, 19 June 1936. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Die 'Schwarze Legion'," Frankfurter Zeitung, 22 June 1936. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "Wie kalkuliert Hollywood?" Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 27 June 1936. Printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "Shirley Temple -- ganz private," Stuttgarter Neues Tagblatt, 28 June 1936. Printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "Neue Handelspolitik zwischen Frankreich und U.S.A.," July ? 1936. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - Untitled writing on Roosevelt's nomination as Democratic Party's candidate for U.S. President, Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 1 July 1936. Printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Die Fronten in USA," Stuttgarter Neues Tagblatt, 2 July 1936. Printed copy (Folder 20)
  - "Roosevelt und Landon," Muenchner Neueste Nachrichten, 2 July 1936. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Die siebenjaehrige Shirley Temple," Hamburger Anzeiger, 6 July 1936. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Kanada-Amerika -- Musterbeispiel guter Nachbarschaft," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 13 August 1936. Printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Der Wandel des Staatskredits in USA," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 24 September -- 10 October 1936. Printed copy (Folder 24)
  - "USA -- Wirtschaft in Wahljahr," Stuttgarter Neues Tagblatt, 12 October 1936 (Folder 25)
  - "USA -- Wirtschaft vor der Wahl," Duesseldorfer Nachrichten, 18 October 1936. Printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "Die Feuerprobe des New Deal," Stuttgarter Neues Tagblatt, 27 October 1936. Printed copy (Folder 27)
  - "Vormarsch der Sojabohne in Amerika," Deutsche Landwirtschaftliche Presse, 31 October 1936. Printed copy (Folder 28)
  - "Roosevelt oder Landon?" Kieler Neueste Nachrichten, l November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 29)
  - "Rendezvous mit dem Schicksal," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 4 November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 30)
  - "Roosevelts Sieg," Duesseldorfer Nachrichten, 5 November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 31)
  - "Nach dem Siege Roosevelts," Stuttgarter Neues Tagblatt, 6 November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 32)
  - "Ergebnisse des Roosevelt-Programms," Deutsche Sparkassen Zeitung, 14 November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 33)
  - "Unsere Meinung," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 21 November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 34)
  - "Roosevelts Aufgabe," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 22 November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 35)
  - "Der Schatten John Marschalls," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 27 November 1936. Printed copy (Folder 36)
  - "Wohin fuehrt Roosevelt die USA?" Volk und Fuehrung, December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 37)
  - "Amerika-Konferenz," Duesseldorfer Nachrichten, 1 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 38)
  - "Pan-Amerika?" Stuttgarter Neues Tagblatt, 1 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 39)
  - "Panamerikanische Zusammenarbeit," Muenchner Neueste Nachrichten, 1 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 40)
  - "Panamerika-Versuche," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 1 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 41)
  - "Die Rolle des Staatskredites in der amerikanischen Konjunkturpolitik," Bank-Archiv, 1-15 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 42)
  - "Pan-Amerikas Friedenskonferenz," Kieler Neueste Nachrichten, 2 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 43)
  - "Wirtschaftliche Hintergruende der Panamerika- Konferenz," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 2 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 44)
  - "Die Konferenz in Buenos Aires," Dresdner Neueste Nachrichten, 3 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 45)
  - "Panamerikanische Zusammenarbeit," Breslauer Neueste Nachrichten, 13 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 46)
  - "Amerikanische Wirtschaftspolitik," Ruhr und Rhein, 18 December 1936. Printed copy (Folder 47)
  - "Panamerikanische Zusammenarbeit auf neuer Basis," January 1937. Printed copy (Folder 48)
  - "Wie sichert USA die erreichte Konjunktur?" Rheinisch-Westfaelische Zeitung, 5 January 1937. Printed copy (Folder 49)
  - "Der Aufstieg John Lewis'," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 12 January 1937. Printed copy (Folder 50)
  - "Neue Grenzen," Stuttgarter Neues Tagblatt, 12 January 1937. Printed copy (Folder 51)
  - "Roosevelts Kongress," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 20 January 1937. Printed copy (Folder 52)
  - "Roosevelts Staatsreform," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 9 February 1937. Printed copy (Folder 53)
  - "USA will seine Prosperitaet sichern," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 10 February 1937. Printed copy (Folder 54)
  - "Die Auseiandersetzung zwischen Kapital und Arbeit in USA," Deutsche Wirtschafts- Zeitung, 18 February 1937. Printed copy (Folder 55)
  - "Produktionsumstellung bei Packard," Ruhr und Rhein, 2 April 1937. Printed copy (Folder 56)
  - "Kampf gegen New York's Gangster," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 3 April 1937. Printed copy and typescript (Folder 57)
  - "Neue Fronten," 20 June 1937. Typescript (Folder 58)
  - "Das neue Antlitz der USA," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 25 June 1937. Printed copy (Folder 59)
  - "Prosperitaet fuer den Farmer," 2 August 1937. Typescript (Folder 60)
  - "'System' besiegt Praesident," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 5 August 1937. Printed copy and typescript (Folder 61)
  - "Zeitberichte," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 6 August 1937. Printed copy and typescript (Folder 62)
  - "Unsere Meinung," Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 7 August 1937. Printed copy (Folder 63)